Guide to the Robert J. Havighurst Papers 1921-1991
University of Chicago Library
Havighurst, Robert J.. Papers
1921-1991
107 linear feet (214 boxes)
Special Collections Research Center University of Chicago Library 1100 East 57th Street Chicago, Illinois 60637 U.S.A.
Robert J. Havighurst (1900-1991), professor and activist. Havighurst was an incredibly active researcher whose work spanned the disciplines of education, psychology, and sociology. He helped to found the Department of Human Development at the University of Chicago. The Havighurst papers primarily contain materials pertaining to his research projects though does include a smaller amount of biographic materials and correspondence and materials pertaining to Havighurst's personal community involvement. Much of the research material pertains to the stages of the life cycle, particularly child development, adolescence and old age. Havighurst's research materials on the study of education are divided by project. His studies focused on small towns, urban schools, and Native American education. The collection also contains some administrative material about the departments of Human Development and Education at the University of Chicago.
Information on Use
Access
Series XV includes evaluative student materials that are restricted until 2043, Havighurst's personnel records, which are restricted until 2027, and a significant collection of recommendations and referee reports, which are restricted until 2015.
The remainder of the collection is open for research.
Biographical Note
Robert J. Havighurst was born in DePere, Wisconsin on June 5, 1900. He grew up in Ohio and Illinois where his father, a former Professor of History at Lawrence College in Wisconsin, served as a Methodist minister. He received his A.B. from Ohio Wesleyan University in 1921 and his Ph.D. in physical chemistry from the Ohio State University in 1924. After a post-doctoral fellowship in physics at Harvard University (1924-1926) and a brief assistant professorship in chemistry at Miami University in Ohio (1927-1928), Havighurst moved gradually away from the physical sciences toward the study of science education, and finally to research, teaching, and consulting in general education. While assistant professor of physics at the University of Wisconsin at Madison (1928-1932), Havighurst also served as advisor in the experimental college there. Committed thereafter to the study of education, he went on to an associate professorship in science education at the Ohio State University (1932-1934), and then to the directorship of the Rockefeller Foundation’s Board of General Education (1934-1940). At the Rockefeller Foundation, Havighurst bridged into the field of developmental psychology, taking over the directorship of the program in child and adolescent development vacated by colleague Lawrence K. Frank.
Havighurst assumed the position of Professor of Education and Executive Secretary to the Committee on Child Development at the University of Chicago in 1940. While at Chicago, Havighurst collaborated with sociologist Ernest W. Burgess to study the social adjustment of retired professionals. The major publications resulting from this research, Personal Adjustment in Old Age (1949), Older People (1953), and The Meaning of Work and Retirement (1954), overturned conventional notions of old age as a period of non-productivity by revealing that the elderly enjoy fulfilling pursuits and a heightened sense of psychological well-being. In the later Kansas City Studies of Adult Life, Havighurst expanded this research to include the study of the process of aging beginning with early middle age. In 1946, along with Burgess and Lawrence K. Frank, Havighurst co-founded the Gerontological Society as an interdisciplinary professional organization, thus pioneering the establishment of gerontology as a social scientific discipline. At the University of Chicago, under Havighurst’s leadership as Executive Secretary (1940-1949) and Chairman (1949-1954), the Committee on Child Development became the Committee on Human Development, broadening its teaching and research agenda to address not only child development but the entire human life cycle from birth to old age. The Ph.D. curriculum developed by the Committee became a model for, and produced the scholars who went on to teach in similar programs at other universities.
At the same time, Havighurst pursued teaching and research on adolescence and education. In small town as well as urban, U.S. as well as comparative international contexts, Havighurst carried out long-term studies of the relationships among social class, culture, moral and practical development, and education. His most influential publications in this area are the widely used textbooks Human Development and Education (1953) and Society and Education (1957, co-authored with Bernice L. Neugarten).
Havighurst was known as an active citizen of Chicago as well as an energetic researcher. He served terms as president of the Hyde Park Community Council and as vice-president of the Citizens Schools Committee of Chicago. He was a member of the City Club of Chicago, director of the Mental Health Society of Greater Chicago, and co-chairman of the Chicago Committee to Defend the Bill of Rights. In 1966 he chaired a meeting at which civil rights activists, pacifists, and other liberal Chicago groups considered banding together to form a third political party. As primary author of a 1964 report on Chicago public schools commissioned by the Chicago Board of Education, Havighurst strongly advocated comprehensive racial integration in Chicago’s public schools. Havighurst died of Alzheimer’s disease at the age of 90 on February 1, 1991.
Scope Note
Robert J. Havighurst (1900-1991), professor and activist. Havighurst was an incredibly active researcher whose work spanned the disciplines of education, psychology, and sociology. Under his auspices, the University of Chicago assumed a pioneering role in the emergence of Human Development as a field of study in its own right. Havighurst served as director of the program in child and adolescent development at the Rockefeller Foundation before assuming the position of Professor of Education and Executive Secretary to the Committee on Child Development at the University of Chicago in 1940. Havighurst's two major areas of research were the social adjustment of retired professionals and the relationships among social class, culture, moral and practical development, and education. He was also active in local Chicago causes pertaining to education, interracial cooperation, and community development.
The Havighurst papers have been organized into ten series: I. Biographical Materials, II. Correspondence, III. General Education, IV. Child Development and Adolescence, V. Society and Education, VI. Morris Study, VII. Quincy Youth Development Commission, VIII. Chicago Schools, IX. Illinois Education, X. Cross-cultural and International Studies, XI. Seneca Research Project, XII. Adulthood, Aging, and the Life Cycle, XIII. Organizations, XIV. Social Issues and Policy, and XV. Restricted. The papers primarily contain materials pertaining to his research projects, though does include a smaller amount of biographic materials and correspondence and materials pertaining to Havighurst's personal community involvement. Much of the research material pertains to the stages of the life cycle, particularly child development, adolescence and old age. Havighurst's research materials on the study of education are divided by project. His studies focused on small towns, urban schools, and Native American education. The collection also contains some administrative material about the departments of Human Development and Education at the University of Chicago.
Related Resources
The following related resources are located in the Department of Special Collections:
http://www.lib.uchicago.edu/e/spcl/select.html
Subject Headings
University of Chicago. Dept. of Education; Adolescence; Adult Education; Child Development; Child Psychology; Education; High Schools -- United States; Older People; Retirement; Urban Schools -- United States; Youth -- Adolescence
INVENTORY
- Series I: Biographical Materials
  - Bibliography, 1924-1952 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Bibliography, 1924-1967 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Bibliography, 1924-1972 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Bibliography, 1924-1977 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Bibliography, 1930-1965 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Bibliography, 1949-1973 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Bibliography, 1960-1967 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Bibliography, 1965-1972 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Bibliography, 1965-1975 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Biographical Materials (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Family Christmas Letters (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Medical Reports (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Creative Writing (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Loyalty Issues (1 of 6) (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Loyalty Issues (2 of 6) (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Loyalty Issues (3 of 6) (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Loyalty Issues (4 of 6) (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Loyalty Issues (5 of 6) (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Loyalty Issues (6 of 6) (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Civilian Personnel Packet (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Loyalty Issues-Personal File (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Loyalty Issues-Investigator’s Report (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Academic Freedom and the Cold War (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Physical Science Research Notebooks-Harvard (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Physical Science Research Notebooks-Harvard and Ohio State (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Reprints, 1924-1933 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Reprints, 1941-1944 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Reprints, 1945-1946 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Reprints, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Reprints, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Reprints, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Reprints, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Reprints, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Reprints, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Reprints, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Reprints, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Reprints, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Reprints, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Reprints, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Reprints, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Reprints, 1959 (1 of 2) (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Reprints, 1959 (2 of 2) (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Reprints, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Reprints, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Reprints, 1962 (1 of 2) (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Reprints, 1962 (2 of 2) (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Reprints, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Reprints, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Reprints, 1965 (1 of 2) (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Reprints, 1965 (1of 2) (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Reprints, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Reprints, 1967 (1 of 2) (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Reprints, 1967 (2 of 2) (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Reprints, 1968 (1 of 3) (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Reprints, 1968 (2 of 3) (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Reprints, 1968 (3 of 3) (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Reprints, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Reprints, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Reprints, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Reprints, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Reprints, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Reprints, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Reprints, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Reprints, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Reprints, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Reprints, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Reprints, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Reprints, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Reprints, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Reprints, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Reprints, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Publication Possibilities (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Accountability and the Teaching Profession, Dec 1, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Social Backgrounds of Disadvantaged Children and Youth, December, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Administrative Organization and a School-Community Plan for the Chicago Public Schools, January 13, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Agriculture and Youth in the Year 2000, February 1976 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Anglo vs. Native Cultures (Correspondence Only) (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Basic Education for American Youth, May 1979 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Big-City High Schools-A Status Report, Feb 1971 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Keeping One’s Options Open Through Career Education, October 12 1974 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - College and the Responsible Mind, June 1968 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Cooperation of Schools With Other Agencies in a City, Dec 1966 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Metropolitan Development and Educational Facilities, April 20, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - The Crisis for Integration in American Education, April 1967 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Education and Value Conflicts, Feb 1972 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - The Esthetic Society, June 29, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - What is the Responsibility and Involvement of Social Welfare in Relation to Childhood Education? (Speech) May 31, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - The Functions of Higher Education in a Metropolitan Area, June 19, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - The Generation Mix (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Youth in Exploration and Man Emergent, June 1962 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Crisis in Higher Education (Notes Only), May 1976 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Social and Educational Implications of Inter-Institutional Cooperation in Higher Education, February 1967 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Metropolitanism and the Issues of Social Integration (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - A Social Systems Analysis of a Metropolitan Area, August 1965 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Human Resources in a Complex Society, April 1966 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Social Change and the Community College, March 1966 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - The Needs of Man (Correspondence and Notes Only) (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Curriculum Implications of Urban Problems for Education, Nov 15 1968 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - New Directions in Secondary Education in Large Cities, February 1969 (Correspondence Only) (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Effects of Occupational Trends on Youth Employment, Nov 1965 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Personalized Instruction and the Developmental Tasks of Children and Youth, January 1972 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - An Educator Looks at Education and Responsible Behavior, April 1966 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Effective Learning in Science, March, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Social and Cultural Changes Molding the Future of the American People (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - The Challenge of Social Change to Education, March 1966 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - The Values of Youth, August 1967 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Overcoming Value Differences, July 1965 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Responsibilities of the Urban School System, May 11, 1968 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Alternative Socioeconomic Structures of a Modern Society (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - The Quality of Urban Education, 1968 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Urbanization and Education in the U.S., November 1966 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Revolution in Education (Notes and Correspondence Only), 1971 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Responsibilities of Education in the Urban Setting (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Scientists, Prophets and Journalists in Education, May 1971 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - The Urban Disadvantaged Child: Needed Research (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Public Education for Disadvantaged Urban Minorities (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Curriculum for the Disadvantaged, Dec 1969 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous Manuscripts (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - A Moratorium on Negative Criticism of Urban Schools (Correspondence only), 1968 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Educational Needs in Relation to Emotional Problems of the Handicapped, Sept 1960 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Characteristics and Needs of Students that Affect Learning (Speech), June 1964 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Public Schools of Chicago (Address), Nov 19, 1964 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Outline-Personality Development (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous Manuscripts, 1962-1965 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous Manuscripts, and Correspondence, 1965-1968 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous Manuscripts and Correspondence (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Social Adjustment in Old Age (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - How Does it Feel to Grow Old? (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - University of Chicago Club of San Francisco Alumni Speech, August 1965 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - You and Your Schools (address) (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Unrealized Potentials of Adolescents (Speech), 1965 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - A Sense of Identity in a World of Diversity, 1966 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous Manuscripts, 1959-1962 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - The Social Bases of Education (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - The Broad Purposes of Education Today (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - The Politics of Big-City Education, Feb 23, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - The Inter-University Consortium for the National Study of American Indian Education, August 1974 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - American Values and the Nature of Moral Character (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Deschooling and Alternative Schools (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Farewell to Schools (Revs and Correspondence), 1974 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Future of Education: Image and Reality, Oct 1972 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Opportunity, Equity, or Equality Through Education, Dec 1972 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - The Teaching of Religion, 1974 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - The American Indian: From Assimilation to Cultural Pluralism (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Contributions of Anthropology to Cultural Pluralism (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Cultural Pluralism and Education, April 1974 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Education and Cultural Pluralism: Structural Aspects, Nov 1977 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Constructive Cultural Pluralism (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - The Broad Purposes of American Indian Education Today (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - The Inter-University Consortium for the National Study of American Indian Education (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - American Values and the Nature of Moral Character (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Indian Education: Accomplishments of the Last Decade, Jan 1981 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Indian Education Since 1960, March 1978 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Education of Native Americans Today, May 1978 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Education, Social Mobility and Social Change in Four Societies (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Review: Education and Brazil, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Who Asks for Reprints of Human Development Journal Articles? (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Scientists, Prophets and Journalists in Education, March 1971 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous Manuscripts (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Politics of Big-City Education, Feb 23, 1976 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Problems of Education (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Personality Change with Aging, 1974 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Teacher Education in New Zealand and the USA: Some Comparisons (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Rights of Individuals and Groups in a Democratic Society-Correspondence and Notes Only, 1974 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Social Perspectives and the Development of Moral Judgments (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Can Educational Sociology Be Objective? (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Youth in Crisis, 1974 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Adult Education and Human Development, 1967 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Review: Human Characteristics and School Learning, August 1976 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Chicago-Educational Development in A Metropolitan Area, 1970 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - The School System and Drugs for Hyperactive Children, May 1976 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Counseling and the Behavioral Sciences, 1979 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Critical Issues In Big-City Education, Nov 1976 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Cultural Pluralism and Education, April 1974 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Review: Education in an Industrial Society (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Common Experience v. Diversity in Curriculum, 1978 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - The Politics of Big-City Education (Lecture), Feb 1976 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Education and Revitalization of the Big Cities, 1980 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Education and Family Life (Lecture), May 1962 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Educationally Deprived Youth, Spring 1969 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Educational Leadership for the 70s, March 1972 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Commentary on Gearing, 1979 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Task Force on Theory Development, 1976 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - The High School in American Society, April 1967 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Higher Education in the Local Community, 1957 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Human Characteristics and School Learning (Review), August 1976 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Human Development and Intergroup Education, May 1945 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Individual and Group Rights in a Democracy, Jan-Feb, 1976 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - The Intellectually Deprived Child, Oct 1963 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - The Junior College in American Society, March 1965 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - The Learning Process, 1961 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - The Development of the Ideal Self in Childhood and Adolescence, Dec 1945 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Discovering and Motivating Scientific Talent (Address) (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Educational Research in the Field of Character Development (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Social Class and Basic Personality Structure, 1952 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - The Significance of Research on Social Structure for Public Education, Dec 1949 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Personality Development, Dec 1947 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Education for Democratic Living (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Review: Adult Development and Learning, 1978 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Over-Productive Youth, 1957 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Review: Dynamics of Prejudice, March, 1950 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Junior High School Youth in Contemporary Society (Address), Feb 12, 1963 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - The Urban Lower-Class School (Speech), April 14, 1962 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - The Influence of Recent Social Changes on the Desire for Social Mobility in the United States (Speech), Oct 1946 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Social Class Influences on American Education, 1960 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Social Class Factors in Coping Style and Competence, August 1971 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - The Postponement of Adulthood, October 1959 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Research on the Development-Task Concept, 1956 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Merriam and Mullins: Havighurst’s Adult Development Tasks: A Factor Analysis, 1979 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - What Adolescence is Like, Sept 1950 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Are We Over-Protecting Our Children? 1951 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Moral Education in the Chicago Area Schools, Lecture, Feb 10 1976 (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Population Growth among Negro Citizens, May 1967 (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - The Neighborhood School, December 1967 (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - Prophets and Scientists in Education, June 1971 (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - The Public Schools and Human Development in the Metropolitan Area, June 5, 1965 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - The Reorganization of Education in Metropolitan Areas, December 1970 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Requirements for a Valid "New Criticism", September 1968 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - The Role of Motivation in Attendance at Post High School Educational Institutions, Feb 1951 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Schools and Disaffected Youth, March 1977 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Teaching Profession (Encyclopedia Britannica), 1974 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Urban Education in the Dark Sixties, Feb 1969 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Urban Problems and Education, Autumn 1963 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - What is the Value of the Social Sciences? (Radio Broadcast), 1954 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Review: Who Gets Ahead? The Determinants of Economic Success in America, 1980 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Alienated Youth: A Statement of National Policy by the Commission on Youth and Work, Dec 1960 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Social Functions of Catholic Education, 1967 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - What is Happening in Education? September, 1965 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Social and School Conditions Productive of Intellectual Superior Children, 1961 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - The Hard-to-Reach Adolescent, Summer 1958 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Non-Learners: The School’s #1 Problem (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Social Classes’ Influences on American Education, 1960 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - National Research Fellowships, 1919-1938 (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Diary-Experimental College, 1930-1931 (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Notes on Greek Civilization-Experimental College, 1928-1932 (Box 15, Folder 20)